And we are live. Good morning. Good
morning. Are you good afternoon?
The morning is just just went by. Yeah,
it's a morning somewhere, right?
Exactly. Depends on how long did you
stay awake and how long did you when did
you wake up?
Okay, [snorts]
actually I meant
there is some people who are not going
to have a good day right now.
>> [laughter]
>> No, they woke up to a
to a ton of [__]
Yeah, that nuts. Like it's crazy and
we're going to need to talk about it
right now.
Okay, so introduction.
Bath, bath, okay, cool.
Are you using NPM?
And do you think you are secure?
Maybe you're not. There is another
supply chain attack on NPM registries
right now and it already happened last
week, couple of days ago.
And
it just burned million of user on
using the all of those packages.
What's the solution? Is it all because
of AI workflows and capabilities?
Watch this video right now and
subscribe.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay, that speed up route but that will
do.
Yeah,
Mitchell, are you updating all of your
package every day?
No. No.
>> [laughter]
>> And not after our conversation from last
week. Yeah.
And really not I'm really sure I'm not
going to update daily after today. It's
it's it's crazy. So, yeah, like what we
So, yeah, this morning
at 6:00 a.m. ET
Socket security, I think I'm going to
follow this account and put them on
notification
every day it's happening, right?
Socket
is investigating an active NPM supply
chain attack compromising hundreds of
package in the NV ecosystem. If they say
investigating, then you're you're
already too late. Yeah. Yeah, like it's
bad because
NPM won't compromise. Where is the
package? NV, yes.
back
path
That's probably not this one. Is it this
No, it's not this one.
Okay, let's go.
Yes.
Oh, it's a Okay, okay, okay.
9 years ago?
What?
What's the package?
Maybe Okay, wait. I'm going to
NV active NPM NV packages
Okay, let's go. What Why Why did I lost
the
technical analysis payload NV
Why can't I find it?
I should have searched
before the stream.
U T components
6 months ago. Is it this one?
Uh could be.
Is it a view? I don't any it because
it's completely
it's not related to TypeScript and
stuff.
But
no no last update, that's not possible.
Yeah yeah, but few years is used a lot
in big Yeah. frameworks.
Wait, do they have the list of package?
Ooh.
No.
Yeah.
Where? Okay, they don't have the list.
Yeah, I had the list somewhere.
Obtain a result of friendly
They added envy setup.
text and dependency mirror technical
provision
love
version skip
network
Oh, yes. Okay, I'm stupid.
It's at the package artifact.
Like electronic
Uh okay, nice. NPM boom.
publish three year what?
Wait, how is that possible to
have a package published three years ago
with a version?
But it's an attack.
Yeah.
>> [snorts]
>> This package has been flagged has been
flagged and fired by signal confirmed.
What?
Wait, okay, let's read the
attack.
So act active supply chain attack
compromise envy packages on NPM active
Oh.
Are we live? Oh oh.
Yeah, you need to restart.
Are you Am I here? Yeah, you're back.
Yes.
Okay, cool.
Nice. Live.
And we are okay, we're still live.
Uh
What's going on?
You keep dropping out.
Damn.
No, that's sad.
I'm Oh.
Okay, no, I'm
Am I here? Yeah, yeah, you're back.
Okay.
Because I can still see you. Okay, it's
probably like a stream. Good.
Uh
whatever.
It goes.
Damn. Okay, so uh
active supply chain compromise and the
packages in fast-moving malicious
published wave tied to mini shy root.
So, it's exactly the same thing than um
uh last week with Stan stack.
Uh Socket thread research. The attack
affected packages tied to the NPM
maintainer account. Oh. Mhm.
Including H
H chart for React.
Back.
Okay.
Uh
H chart for React.
Nice.
H chart for React, a widely used React
wrapper for Apache H charts with roughly
1 million
weekly download.
Okay, H chart for React.
Back. Back.
Uh
4 months ago. They probably deprecated
some versions.
Latest beta.
Yeah.
Uh
A widely used React wrapper for Apache
ECharts was Roshan. Socket quickly
detected the malicious published web and
classified the affected version as known
malware.
Uh
the affected packages that include
widely used NV package such NVG2, G6,
X6. What What the [__] is that?
Did you ever use any of those?
Well, I don't, but I think the biggest
issue is that most people don't know
what they use because if you install a
package, it can include additional
packages.
Yeah. Oh yeah, yeah, because yeah, you
install package and then it's a
dependency of someone else, so you can't
even track it, but it's uh yeah, you
have the whole collection behind it.
Yeah. And even if you then just redeploy
your project because you did a small
update on something that doesn't impact
anything, it reinstalls all the packages
and it installs all the malicious code
and steals your codes and your account.
Yeah.
Good. Okay. Uh so yeah, we already
talked about that last week, but like do
you think there is a world when every
like each developer will rewrite their
own packages?
I don't think they will do that, but if
you have
code that can never go offline,
to be honest, right now you always have
your your install every NPM package
every time that you deploy.
Yeah. So if you want to have a really
stable code, I know it a lot of
developers are going to hate the
solution, but
download it once and just push it in the
deploy and don't install it.
Install it one Yeah, but I mean like
when you deploy, you also freeze the
version.
Well, not everybody does that.
Oh, they Yeah, I mean You can freeze the
version, but if you use package one and
that's the only one that you include and
that includes additional other ones, it
can still install the latest updates of
the other ones, even if you set the
version to a static version.
>> Oh, yeah. So, the dependency is on
latest uh version,
and you install always the same, but the
dependency will be
That will be the malicious ones, and
that's the biggest issue, I think.
Because you don't know what the other
ones are, and you don't even care
because you trust on your NPM package
that it's correct. Yeah. And then it
works.
Isn't that the biggest issue that people
trust the the code from other devs and
just install it without looking? But
there's way too much to research
everything. Yeah, exactly. Like, welcome
to open source software.
Yeah.
Like, you push you push something
publicly, it's used by a million of
other people, and then you get [__]
because you forget your 2FA on your
ex-girlfriend's
phone.
Yes.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
That's
That's a problem, for sure. Okay, so
this one
consists of progressive visualization
grammar. It's a visualization grammar
for dashboard building, data
exploration, and storytelling.
What? Yeah, but I don't know if you go
to the GitHub URL, if
packages as well.
Uh I don't know Yeah, what's happened
with your mic, but you were underwater.
Oh. I'm back or not yet? Yeah, it's
good.
Uh
Go to the GitHub URL, if you can see
that it includes additional packages as
well.
Oh, yeah, you have you will have the
dependencies, right? Yeah.
It should be there.
So, package.
Oh, wait.
Wait. You want dependencies.
And you never check these because you
just
only install one,
and it installs everything additional.
Yeah.
Yeah, and like because it's like a
carrot.
Is it a carrot?
Like a yeah, was exposed on exposed
Uh
you you install all of the version above
like 2.1.9. So,
you can install three.
And three is compromised.
Exactly. But
And then the next question is what if
that dependency installs additional
dependencies dependencies?
Yeah. Yeah.
I don't know if people know how many
they install when they deploy something
because they don't check it. They just
trust that it works. Every time I
install like a NPM package then I have a
node module of like 3 GB of garbage.
Especially in the mono repo, right?
Because you have all of the package of
API blah blah blah. But then you you
also have um
a bun uh package manager that are also
smart. So, they are like installed like
version of it then it's cached and then
you don't need to redownload it, but
then it's like symlinked correctly
inside the the project. So, you don't
download the same
40 GB of uh node modules every time you
switch a project. Yeah, but developers
know how that works. People who are just
doing vibe coding I mean
>> [clears throat]
>> they just accept everything. And the
only test they do is when I click the
button does it do what I wanted to do?
Yeah, no exactly. But also like a vibe
coder will not have an impact of a
million dollar company that in revenue
is like proper setup, you know?
I have seen some vibe coders who just
say, "Okay, I want to have some software
to manage my leads and my clients. Let
me just vibe code it, deploy it on
lovable, and just load in all my
customer data."
People are vibe coding really
important [__] and not thinking about
security.
Yeah.
Okay. May
Do you think they played communicated
about that?
I don't think so. That's not a problem,
right?
I trust in replicate agent. Yeah, I
know.
I mean, that's not the audience like
they don't they don't want to talk about
security issue, I guess.
Uh
like
Uh publish technical under the package
is carried out. What was the maintenance
account become the blast radius package
level radius already too late. Thank
you, AI.
Yeah, but then the question is what do
you do right now?
If you need to deploy or update your
project,
are you going to just do it? Are you
going to wait?
Like
I mean, yeah, like for example, for
after our conversation on burn, I set up
like the
uh 3 days or 3 hours. I think 3 hours
because 3 days was like too long. Mhm.
But uh so, yeah, I have this thought,
but um
yeah.
Those issues are like
caught up really quickly, though.
Yeah, yeah. I think they trigger
instantly some some notification
somewhere and then
I think then you need a dev who is going
to check it, right?
Yeah, I know. Exactly. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, see basically that is acquire NPM
and Mentos flash go into safety.
Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> I am really If you see what Mentos has
done in the in the last weeks, the the
big leaks that it found, Yeah.
Uh
Mentos We are not safe at all.
I think I
I see.
Like
Uh
I see.
What is it? What What was the issue?
I think Mitus was the one that also
found the the the leak in the Apple M5,
right?
Apple
M5
Yeah, and if you see how much money they
spend on improving it
and they found it in just a few days.
Yeah, yeah, it's not and also Mitus is
coming, right? So, that would be
interesting. Uh,
Mitus
version 4.6
I
Naruto, I'm not sure about Naruto. What
is it?
Uh, Google
if you
Yeah.
Google Mitus Yes, I think that's the
one. Yes.
Uh, Anthropic Cloud Mitus model has been
spotted on Google Cloud Console. Cloud
Mitus, it's hard to imagine that
Anthropic would change its mind and
release it publicly, but they could act
as a model provider for those company
who have access to the model and wrote
that their stuff on Google Cloud
Platform. Yeah, so you need to ask uh
permission to use it. Yeah. But uh yeah,
because even it's expensive, it's still
expensive as far as I can remember, but
if you are Google, you want to have
access to it, right? Yes.
But it's coming. It's this Cloud Mitus
is coming. So, yeah, what's going to
happen
um
in the next few weeks, that's going to
be interesting.
What if without Cloud Mitus we get like
big hacks like this one on the NPM
packages?
I think you can call those the small
ones if you see what's coming. Yeah, But
it's going to be interesting.
>> [laughter]
>> Everybody was laughing about these.
But what if if cloud meters can find it
and disguise it so that the firewall
doesn't find it?
Or the security check. So there is no
ping to a deaf one, "Hey, something
weird happened here." It just is done as
separate functions that just
control it together. Yeah.
Yeah. That makes it really hard.
And it's the same thing like we had the
the attacks last week where they faked
the credential where they faked the The
cache the cache poisoning, right?
Yeah, people didn't see it. Or they and
then they come on to a desktop and they
try to fake
um like like the security and everything
so that your device trusts the new
update.
Yeah, then you're already too late.
Yeah, and then you update to the new the
new version but it's already cracked
too.
>> Yeah, it it uses the certificates that
the application normally uses as well.
So it all looks legit. Yeah, but because
it's all
it's in the cache, right? So you have
been validated by the right certificate
in the cache and then the cache is
getting like it is got I mean
it will be validated after
the legit push used the cache of the
infected uh request. So
Yes, but but that's why like the whole
trust publisher setup and in NPM it's
garbage.
But yeah. But the problem is like
GitHub knew and even NPM so because NPM
got bought by GitHub Mhm. a few years
ago, I think like 5 6 years ago, and it
bought it bought by Microsoft.
So NPM is part of Microsoft. Yeah, well
And we have the same issues on NPM that
people are like screaming about on about
GitHub.
Yeah. I think Microsoft has a lot of
leaks right now. Yeah, it's not.
Like yeah, use Google platform access to
meet us to investigate all of your
Microsoft product.
It's it's crazy.
Yeah, but does this mean that security
is going to be the next uh
multi-billion dollar market for every
dev? For sure.
Like it's
security is hard
and everyone will have access to
security skills with a smart model.
So Yeah, but not everybody uses how to
know it.
Yeah.
>> give everybody tools, but they don't
know how to build the house. But do you
need to know security issues to use
cloud to prompt and attack a domain name
that have been vibe coded by
a 6-year-old that is
going to cut before it start cutting?
No, no, [laughter] no. No, not by vibe
coded uh
applications. Those should be easy.
Yeah.
So yeah, and then you can vibe code like
a stripe like app and then you got a
stripe card number.
>> Even vibe coders even don't add the
functionality to add a security against
brute force or something. So
They don't think about it. They just
vibe code and say I need a login. You
don't think about it because you don't
know about it. Yeah, that's the issue.
Uh
this is really bad. Yeah, also technical
analysis malicious payload a review of a
compromised and the artifact identified
install time payload consistent with a
mini shade Hulu supply malware family a
root level index payload modified
package.json to execute it during
installation. Yeah, like um there is I
think it's PM PM that
you can block every NPM package that
have a pre-install
uh
script.
Yes, but then your project doesn't work.
I mean not
Yeah, and you need to debug everything
manually. Yeah.
Uh injected file is heavily obfuscated.
It use a large string array. Look at the
table, runtime screen, blah blah blah.
Yeah, okay, whatever. Uh collected data
is analyzed. Okay, so yeah. I mean it's
a pre-install attack again. Yeah.
And then the next issue is because of
course if you have this in your
development machine, you're using not
using real API keys. Everything is
dummy. Everything is going to something
different than not the live location.
But it also steals your GitHub
credentials, so it has access to
everything. Yeah.
I mean yeah. I don't want to know how
many people secretly have some passwords
or
AI keys, API keys in their in their
code. Yeah.
I mean you can
scan that on GitHub right now. But even
like
you know on AWS and Google Cloud, you
have secret manager
uh vault, right? Mhm. [clears throat]
So
instead of having those [__] dot env
install files,
everyone should use those secret vault.
Yes. On cloud platform. Yeah, protect
them with good password and make sure
they're encrypted. And yeah, probably
need to nuke all of those dot
env.production files. Yeah, yeah. And if
you have them, please replace all the
passwords and regenerate new ones. I
mean for now, I don't know about you,
but like I don't get any
impacted by any of those packages. I'm
not going to say that out loud. I know
how that works. Because next week we
have to reschedule because I'm doing
[laughter]
hot fixes everywhere, but yeah, right
now
and it is not that I'm not using the
software that's getting hacked, but
I'm just reviewing everything, checking
everything before I publish, before I
push. Don't use the latest versions.
Just being careful. Do you use Socket?
Almost not. Yeah, maybe maybe we should
do a live stream on to install Socket.
How to install Socket Socket and how to
get hacked.
I mean, I can do it. Am I connected?
Uh perfect. Yeah, I'm not connected on
that account. But uh yeah, I I think uh
yeah, I think I I have that in my to-do
list.
But um
yeah, probably going to have like add
more one more GitHub action.
Like
perfect perfect
add
Socket
to
projects.
>> [snorts]
>> But do you think it will become worse
and
then what are we going to do to fix it?
What? About Socket? About the No, no,
about the NPM attacks and everything.
Yes. Uh wait.
So like um yes, it is it's going to get
worse for sure.
Because again, like more people are
building stuff, more people are vibe
coding stuff, and the models are getting
smarter.
Um
to have
to to run security pen test and all
everything that's what we paid like 5
years ago some security firm to check
the our infrastructure for 15 grand,
right? So
everyone everyone can can create a new
business that will be yeah, will you
will charge like 500 bucks a month and
you can monitor security stuff.
So, yeah.
Like
Where there is money to be made, there
is like
uh
more people to try to do it, right?
Yeah. And
>> think security is going to be a bigger
and bigger part of coding.
It's going to be
I mean, it we have to secure apps
anyway, right? Or Yeah, but before when
you got somewhere, the first question
you got is hey, do you write Python? Can
you write PHP? Can you do a React yes?
And everybody [clears throat] can do all
of those right now. Mhm. Because you
have AI. So, the next question is what
are you going to do to make sure to make
sure that our servers are secure?
Yeah. I mean
>> How fast do you act when you see that
something is getting hacked or that
there's an issue?
I mean, like I would I would almost say
like it's on the
on the bigger providers like for example
Cloudflare or Amazon or yeah, Google
Cloud Platform to solve those issues.
Because everyone is impacted. Well, I
haven't Vercel. Like for example, you
have a front end, Vercel can have an
agent running searching for all of the
package of every [__] project they're
pushing.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, they can, but
That's Yeah. That's big. But
>> Yeah. I think they can have an other
plugin like the pro version then you
start paying for that as a useful like
five bucks a month add-on stuff. Mhm.
And then you say, "Okay, monitor all of
my project and tell me which version
blah blah blah."
That That's an infrastructure play,
right? And you need that you you need
like socket.dev applications, no?
More than ever, I guess.
Yeah. Because you will have agent that
will attack, but you will have defenders
agent, too.
Yeah, it will
it will be an AI war. Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
Uh I mean, that would be that would be a
good business, for sure.
Can we fight code SocketDev?
Yeah, we can fight code it. I'm just
curious how long does it take before you
get your first hack, and then it's
completely gone.
Yeah, yeah, I mean, because yeah, people
are trying to attack your your shield.
We should do like shield
ship ship dev.
Yeah, open source. I think if we if we
just
um
create a a management portal for your
version control and notifications,
that's the first big setup. Yeah.
Yeah, okay. So, you attach your repo,
you watch all of the version of the
packages, and you see what's uh
Yeah, and we just keep scraping all the
updates and all the security issues, and
check everything. Mhm.
Yeah. Well, that's pro that's probably
what Socket is doing, anyway. Yeah,
yeah. I I I'm really sure they're doing
that.
But that yeah, that makes sense. We're
not going to make those projects like
mandatory, for sure. Yeah. But you were
going to show us how to set it up,
right?
Oh, yeah. I mean, yes, I can.
Tada! There it is. Hot crazy hot.
Install. Yeah, I'm going to
it sign. Okay, I'm going to I'm going to
stop.
We need to do like this, huh? So, we
don't see your password.
Okay.
Tag unlock path.
Tag.
Path. Yeah, and then I'll allow
two-factor authentication code 444.
>> [laughter]
>> I have the
I have the
uh one password.
I don't know that.
That's a way.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh install.
Uh
change feed. Why not?
Let's get off.
Off.
Let's go.
Out of my emails. Let's go.
>> [laughter]
>> Nobody's watching. You can cut it out
later.
Let's work Almost there.
Link installation. Ready.
Insta What? Oh, okay.
Okay. Organization. Organization.
Change.
.ai
repository workspace.
Welcome to the new site.
Next, uh,
sidebar menu. Yes, thank you. You have a
sidebar menu. Let's go.
Okay. Okay. User settings. Okay. Help
information. Okay. Secure product. Let's
go. So, repo.
This feature is not available in the
Really?
You need to pay first.
I don't want to pay first. I want to try
first.
Why do you have a free plan if you can't
do anything free? Because it's free.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh, or maybe it's not on the
on the
It is What?
Oh, wait. Connect
configure a change feed repository.
A
What?
Okay, I guess I'm going to install that
offline in because it doesn't make
sense.
But, uh, I don't that Why would I
connect the repository if I can't do
anything?
Dependencies, okay, currently, okay.
Or did I install No, you don't install
it correctly.
Oh.
Block default ideal for commerce, okay.
Block one supply chain amount Okay, so
that's an example, right?
Okay.
Yeah, this is an example.
>> Yeah, it's an example.
Yeah, whatever. Uh legal
publicity or building, whatever.
Okay, I'm going to I'm going to install
it and then I will report it. I'm going
to make a tweet to see if it's useful or
not.
Uh threat intel
Let me see Ruby on Rails, okay.
We're viewing a limited set of attack
campaign, okay.
Okay, I'm I'm going to organize that for
Oh.
Manage boards develop GitHub.
Oh, it was the scan, okay. Generate
generating scan result. Okay, cool.
Okay.
I don't know what's the what happened,
but
uh
>> Yeah, it's over 30% already.
That's nice. Wait, but what's Okay, I
don't understand what's the
difference between that
I don't know. I have never used it.
>> and that.
Okay, so let's check that.
Please don't like any
Maybe you have to check it offline
first.
Uh path, okay.
So, I'm going to We're going to keep
that running.
Um okay, cool. So, yeah, NPM Next.js, we
talked about that.
Uh yeah, Mozilla
path
Yeah, yeah, maybe
we can check those.
Um yeah, Reddit
>> [snorts]
>> Reddit post uh maintainer account got
got hacked blah blah blah, but what's
interesting is like the secret like NPM
is known for non being crazy secure, no?
The S in NPM stands for security.
>> [laughter]
>> All right.
The blockchain attack blah blah blah.
Okay.
Uh
is it impractical to go off on a bug
fixed release in three 30 days? Then
depend about post to script update.
Uh disable build scripts or would you
require uh any release to be a day a
week
three to five days?
Yeah.
Maybe I should increase that. I'm not
sure.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm really sure. If they are just too
late by not giving a notification, three
hours is not that much. Yeah, true.
Uh people need to stop using this nano
packages. Time ago, you can throw that
yourself. Every dependency you take is
an supply chain risk.
Yeah, cool that. Yeah.
I mean, yeah, I would again, are we
going to rewrite every like React
component or like PHP module stuff that
uh
If you have a lot of customers, you
might just you can have AI recreate
everything. Yeah. Yeah, I mean You set
up your own thing. Yeah, you you can you
can get like the repository. Yeah, but
then like you're going to ask AI to
rewrite it and then the AI will re will
will rewrite it with like the same
package and say, "Yeah, it's done." No,
no, no. Yeah, actually just build it
yourself.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
Depending on how complex it should be,
but that should be no issue at all.
What's the package manager for PHP?
P N P M P P No, no.
No, no, no. I'm using composer just. I
composer, yes.
Uh study one scanning still scanning or
what? Are we moving? We not moving.
Okay, cool. Let's go.
Uh
not super easy with time zone. Okay,
whatever. Uh could be potential was a
error of slope, yeah.
The P N N What does this keep happening
to you?
Only package manager where is it
happening regularly?
Why does this keep happening to us? Ask
only
What?
NPM since the Windows for package
manager, yeah.
Bad.
Uh
like uh
behind the scenes
hardening Firefox with Cloud Metos.
Like, if we have browser's issues
directly,
that's going to be fun, too.
Yeah.
Yeah. I think most of the people won't
even know that there are issues at the
moment. Yeah. But there probably are.
T
A 15-year-old bug in the legend element
triggered by meticulous orchestration of
H keys across distant part
uh parts of the browser including weaker
recursion stack death limit
expando properties and cycle collection
like
>> [snorts]
>> Okay.
Cool.
A raw 9 crossing an IPC boundary can
masquerade as a tagged GS object
pointer.
Cool.
How do you find those bugs? Yeah, that's
why I have Metos. But that's also if
they didn't find the bugs for 15 years,
Yeah, no, exactly. That if we didn't
have AI, it could be in there for
another 15.
Yeah, easy. That's what we had with like
the uh
OpenBSD
kernel issue, right? Yeah.
Um
AI will be the answer of AI issues.
But maybe these are just the hiccups
that that we need to go through to get
everything optimized in security. Yeah.
Uh say again?
Right now our security we think our
security is good because
uh pen test people don't find all the
issues. We have 15-year-old bugs and we
never found them and we are happy with
how everything is going. It's not
getting hacked. But AI is coming in, so
maybe this is just a transitioning
phase. Yeah, exactly. I think so.
>> For everything to improve security.
Yeah.
And I'm really sure if somebody comes
and says, "Hey, we have a new solution
for NPM packages. We can do the same,
but we can do it secure. Nothing goes
into your system without a double check
up front."
Then everybody switches. Yeah. Not
exactly. Yeah, yeah, again, like if the
whole the big providers have access to
the model like 3 months before the
public, then the race is like it's okay,
right? Yeah, yeah, they will make sure
that a lot of bugs and issues are solved
before it even reaches us.
>> Yeah.
Oh, or And they have to. That's the
That's their income.
Yeah, no, exactly. But it it's Yeah, but
it makes sense again to reach that
point, too. And we will get there like,
okay. So, first,
uh
thanks for
uh Ross for your comment. I've reached
the point where I no longer wants to
download anything from anywhere due to
the fear of contamination of everything.
Yeah, it's crazy.
Like, that's I think that's the point of
a lot of uh where a a lot of developer
are right now. Yeah. Yeah. And with bugs
before you and and security issues, you
need to download it first and on
execution, you get the issue. So, you
can scan it, but this is during the
installation. This is This is a bigger
issue. And it's
Yeah. It it sounds like, you know like
in crypto when
when you we have when we had like some
new stuff to try on new tools etc.
If it was a download
exam or like DMG whatever you don't you
just don't do it. No. Like a lot of
YouTubers are getting attacked like
that. They don't know the PDF and then
they get [__] right?
>> Yeah, yeah, there was a script in the
PDF. We are here
with Dev. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> And still it's impossible to check
everything. Yeah. Yeah, exactly. Yeah,
how do you install like for example ship
code?
Are you going to run like a brew install
ship code which is like a ID slasher
project management tool for AI and then
I think yeah I think
How could how could I get
authentic
orchestrator? Yes. An orchestrator and
I'm going to install that on my computer
and maybe the bundle is corrupted.
Well, the only thing I can do is I still
have my Mac mini here that's that's
clean.
I just use it for testing. That's it.
Are you going to test every component in
a docker container then?
No, but if that's needed and that's the
only thing to keep it secure, how many
choices do you have? Exactly.
But then I would rather because okay, I
had docker on local because it's taking
like 40 gigabytes for a [__] one
container. Yes. So then
we are going to do local host Dev in the
cloud.
Yeah, or just have a big server at your
own place. Yeah.
Yeah, we are going back to hardware.
I'm really sure that a lot of companies
going back to locally hosted servers in
their own
offices with a big firewall in front of
it. And the only way to get in is a VPN.
Yeah.
Yeah, but then you you will have like
AWS
instances and then all of you there will
connect to those instances. I don't know
how that works in like a big company
like if they have
There is basically like a your computer
is just like a Google Google What was
the computer like the Google the
the the one one hundred percent in the
cloud. Yeah, the Chromebooks. Yeah, the
Chromebook. Everything would be a
Chromebook that's connected to your
internal server and you code on that and
all of the agent are running on that
blah blah blah and you just pro because
you don't need resources anymore. Yeah,
but it's the same that they did with the
thin clients, right? The smaller PCs and
you just use Windows log into an
external computer and you work in the
external computer.
That's it.
A virtual desktop.
I like that. I [clears throat] [__]
maybe I should do that for myself
anyway.
Because even to run like like my issue
on my local machine right now it's like
when I test like end-to-end test. Mhm.
[__] annoying to to run and like it's
just killing my CPU and then I like say
oh what's going on?
Mhm. Now I understand why
Theo was upset that you can't
drag and drop an image via SSH in the
cloud CLI. Yeah, because that makes it
harder because you want to do it here
and then drag it through the SSH and
your cloud is running on the other side.
Okay.
Damn.
And that's what I like with the the the
Mac shared windows.
If you have all your working places on
the Apple ID and in the same environment
and your same local setup,
you can just open a window see the auto
Mac, and drag and drop between Macs.
That works perfectly.
Oh.
Yeah, but my Mac mini is too small to
manage anything. But, yeah.
Hmm.
Okay, I have so many ideas of
implementation of [__] I just think
that
we need different setups.
Even if you have multiple big customers,
you can't have them all on the same uh
working place. You need like two Mac
minis and separate them, or whatever. If
one gets Even if you're not in full
control of all the code Uh
and another dev is working on that as
well, you don't know what he is pushing
and you you need to check everything.
So,
you want to separate it.
Yeah.
[__] Want to total isolation. Yeah.
Frictionless totally segregation between
project and stuff. Yeah, but try
explaining that you to your biggest
customer that they got hacked because
another dev from smaller company was
working with you on a small project.
That's impossible. Yeah.
Yeah, Jesus.
I mean, yeah, okay.
Uh why we on this page?
>> [laughter]
>> You were checking the the Metos what it
was doing for Firefox. Exactly.
And this chart is also like speaking for
itself because Okay, bug fixes by
months. And since they have Metos, they
also found those issues. So, those
issues were founded by Metos uh for
Well, got founded by Metos and they got
fixed by Metos. It would be cool to have
the employee account working on the bug
fixing
uh in this table as well.
Oh, yeah.
To com Yeah.
To compare how many people were fixing
bugs, and then you see Metos coming and
you have less people working on bug
fixing, but you have like a 6x on the
amount of bugs that it fixed.
I mean, it's probably like
I don't have an expect like a lot of new
software engineer using metas to find
bugs. It's just like
uh slash go find bugs. Yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> And solve them. Uh
Uh yeah, takeaways. Anyone building
software can start using an harness with
a modern model to find bugs in Arden
that codes today. We recommend getting
started now. You will find bugs and you
will set yourself to take advantages of
new models as soon as they become
available. Yeah.
Um in all of my project, I don't know if
you use that maybe not because
you're doing some PHP stuff, but React
Doctor
Uh like this one.
Uh I'm running that
uh actions and even like on on my pull
request
to detect like yeah, if I can find any
you know, loop with like use effect and
stuff like that with React React Doctor
and I try to reach 100% Uh like I'm
refactoring a project right now and it's
full it's not it was like 24. I'm just
like cleaning that.
Um based on the recommendation of other
and like better software engineers
stuff. So, I like that. And I have uh
[__] I um
Vercel
DeepSec
from Vercel Labs. So, it's
>> [clears throat]
>> a Git.
Um
NPM NPX DeepSec in it.
Uh it's basically like doing some code
review
in the security aspect of it.
Uh and then cool vulnerability scanner
that you can run in your own
infrastructure optimized to perform on
demand review of all code in existing
large-scale repo. So, for a mono repo, a
gigantic like mono repo stuff, deep
sack.
And uh Peter
also launched a new one. Uh Peter
glow patch.
I think I sent you that.
Um
glow patch.
Yes.
Automated code review with explicit
fixes.
And I have this package running again.
Uh
to check
my code base, my mono repo. Um I I like
to reach 100% or 80 plus. It's It's the
new test coverage, basically. Yeah, but
this shows that you're you're you're not
developing yourself anymore. You are a
team lead setting up everything to make
sure that it works perfectly. Yeah.
Yeah. So, hopefully those all of those
combination of packages are helping me
like uh create uh
better apps, at least more secure. Mhm.
And not doing like some crazy uh obvious
issues.
Uh
yeah, feature mapping, code review. So,
feature mapping, you will have all of
the yeah, features of your software and
it will try It will base on the features
map to then uh have the code review. It
will um
What do we say? Uh
exactly. Uh
each feature is include includes entry
point, own files,
context files. And as she said, test
giving AI reviewer the right context to
understand your code. So, yes, that's a
Yeah, that's to build the context of the
the next task, which it will be the code
review. Mhm. And that's why it's split
by features. Yeah, you need a proper
documentation first before you can do
the actual testing. And glow patch does
all of that. So, from time to time, I
run glow patch on my code and I try to
reach um
a high score. And when it's everything
more stable then I will push to
GitHub actions and then like keep
running on pull request. Yes. It's like
code rabbit, gray tile, all of that.
I mean, I don't I don't see a
a disadvantage of loading as as many
like a good providers of security and
code review. So, let's go.
Yeah, that sounds good. It's a It's a
good basis. Yeah, I know, exactly. I
mean, it's better than just me not doing
any of that, so.
And just pushing.
Uh
cool. Okay, so next GS we talked about
that.
Uh yeah.
Oh.
Uh you you think that only NPM package
packages are [__] but also curl.
Curl is impacted by those security
issues.
Uh non-access AI has kind of curls
before the first mythos report. We had
already scanned curl with several
different very capable AI powered tools.
Addition of running number of normal
static code analyzer, blah blah blah.
Uh
Uh of the years primarily well, whatever
whatever. It was scrutinized the code
with AI those tools and analyzed they
have
They have done have triggered somewhere
between two and 300 bug fix merging
curl.
Uh
so, yeah, you can already find something
with like smaller models. But then,
nowadays we also use like copilot, blah
blah blah.
Where is it? Oh, yes. Okay. Uh
great and the first source code analysis
report generated with mythos another
chance for us to find areas to improve
and bug fix.
Makes it a better curl. The initial scan
was made on curl git repository and its
master branch of a certain it contained
170 lines of code analyzing the assets
subdirectory. I thought it was errors.
It's going to be errors. We found 200k
errors. No, no, no, no. It just They I
don't think they are even going to tell
you. They're first going to fix it.
Yeah, yeah. No, but that I think that's
Mitosis find the current vulnerability.
Yeah, okay. One.
Find a current vulnerability, right?
Yeah. Uh
Mitosis performed a search and has
focused a phone not in the top of the
report.
One of the most frozen audited C code
base in existence, blah, blah, blah.
Is unlikely, okay. Found no problems in
this area.
Types of curl finding Five findings
become one. The report concluded it
confirmed five confirmed security
vulnerability. I think use the term
confirmed is a little amusing.
Five issues felt like nothing and were
not expected an executive list.
Um
The single confirmed vulnerability is
going to end up a severity low
CVE plan to get publication sync.
Uh blah, blah, blah.
Not particularly dangerous, okay.
Can however not end up
with anything else than the big hype
around this model so far was primarily
marketing.
Yeah, but but the biggest danger why
Mitosis is dangerous, it finds so many
small leaks and so many small bugs and
combines them into one big exploit.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know. Exactly.
People don't even understand that all
the separate small issues
are giving you the option to get
exploited. So Yeah. I It's like you
know, like in a plane crash, right? Like
when a plane crash occurs, it's not only
one small or one big
defect. It's like 25 Yeah. small issues
that compounded and then the plane
crashes.
>> It can fly without one of the engines.
It can fly without this, without that,
but if it's always combined,
you have big problem. Yeah, exactly.
Exactly. So, yeah, it looks like it's
going to be like uh
uh
cat and cat and mouse. Who do you say
that?
So, when do you expect the next one? We
have the NPM packages today, so tomorrow
morning we will have the next big one?
>> Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You can have You can have like the
um socket accounts notification on and
they will tweet.
You will get up to 50 tweets. They they
they will they will they will tweet
again. Yeah. Maybe maybe we should all
like follow and subscribe to them for
sure because it's not the last one. But
then, the other question, eh?
Um everybody was also talking about
slash gold going to bed, waking up the
next morning and your code base was
updated fully with everything and it was
working while you're sleeping. Do you
even trust that with all these hacks?
It's
Again, like um I think quality
review is
um
it's mandatory, of course. Like you need
to review, but again, like you can't
review everything
by yourself that AI can do because then
you become the bottleneck. Yeah. All
right. The problem I have right now is
like on the front end side, the AI is
still not do like keeping consistency
between the pre the previous component
to you to use that to use it like
properly 100% of the time. Mhm.
Sometimes it's great like an element
that I didn't ask it. It's a It's a
small scope, right? But you can have the
same um
the same kind of uh hack from the the
models to pass a quality gate, for
example. Like
the first run of the React Doctor, Mhm.
when I run it on a new code base, it
uh it disabled all of the check rules. I
said, "Oh, yeah, we reached 100%." I
said.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, yeah. What did you do?
But but I
For example, when that happened, like
the next step is like me creating a
skills react doctor and uh don't uh
create filters for the
fix everything, fix the errors, and then
fix the warning, blah blah blah.
It just
You're talking to an intern and you need
guidance. That's it.
>> Yeah. Because
if you cannot find any issues, then
you're 100% safe.
Yeah, I'm saying so.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, man, it's
It's a strange world, but uh yeah. We're
we're still trying to figure out anyway,
right? Yes. Yeah.
What do you think?
I think we just keep on going because we
are secure so far and we are doing
proper checks, we have proper setups, we
don't just push everything. So,
it's about knowing what you're doing as
well and not just white coding. Mhm.
>> [clears throat]
>> Yeah. I mean, like uh yeah, we probably
like minorly we are probably like
injected some
uh
security vulnerabilities and we we are
not aware of it.
Yeah, well,
they will get fixed eventually. Yeah.
Inshallah.
Okay, that's the We should stop here,
right?
Yeah, I think we did most of it. Yes.
So, that's going to be a good intro. So,
yeah, thank you, Michelle. Thank you,
Ross, for your comments. I don't know if
you're still here, but if you're still
here, thank you for watching and for the
watch hours.
Thank you. And uh yeah, Michelle, uh
enjoy the rest of your day. Thank you.
Same for you. Everyone else, subscribe,
comment, uh help us with the algo the
algorithm
because uh we need subscribers. So,
let's go.